The Mainprice Deposit
The Mainprice Deposit
- The Chetham/Clowes Deeds, 15th century-19th century; GB/418/E.7.7-E.7.12 & E.8.3-E.8.14; GB/418/Main/2; 747 files; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to land in Kersal, c 1540-19th century; GB/418/E.7.10, 7.11, 8.4, 8.12A; GB/418/Main/2/3; 46 files; Chetham's Library
    - Deed concerning land in Kersal, 4 &5 Oct 1609; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 1, no 1 & 2; GB/418/Main/2/3/1; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From Robert Ravald (1588-1629) of Kersal to James Chetham, Richard Edge, James Wroe and Richard Ravald
    - Bond in £100 from Robert Ravald (1588-1629) to James Chetham to perform covenants, 4 Mar 1612; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 1, no 3; GB/418/Main/2/3/2; Chetham's Library
    - Deed concerning land in Kersal, 5 Mar 1612; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 1, no 4a & 4b; GB/418/Main/2/3/3; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From Robert Ravald (1588-1629) to James Chetham, Richard Edge, James Wroe and Richard Ravald.
      (4b) is a draft of (4a).
    - Bargain and sale of land in Kersal, 6 Mar 1612; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 1, no 5; GB/418/Main/2/3/4; Chetham's Library
      From Robert Ravald (1588-1629) to Richard Edge.
    - Assizes at Lancaster referring to land in Kersal, 1612; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 1, no 6; GB/418/Main/2/3/5; Chetham's Library
      Mentions James Wroe, Richard Ravald senior and James Edge.
    - Lease of land in Kersal, 20 Aug 1616; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 1, no 7; GB/418/Main/2/3/6; Chetham's Library
      From Robert Ravald (b.1563), Robert Ravald (1588-1629), James Chetham of Crumpsall and Richard Edge of Ollerforest to John Byrtnshawe.
    - Memorandum concerning purchase by Samuel Chetham of land in Kersal belonging to Edward Bent, 17 Jan 1699; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 2, no 8; GB/418/Main/2/3/7; Chetham's Library
    - Notes concerning Samuel Chetham's purchase of Bent's estate in Kersal, 14 Mar 1699/1700; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 2, no 9; GB/418/Main/2/3/8; Chetham's Library
    - Receipt for £500 from Edward Bent to Samuel Chetham in payment for land in Kersal, 5 Jun 1700; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 2, no 10; GB/418/Main/2/3/9; Chetham's Library
    - Bond in £1000 from Edward Bent and Samuel Chetham to perform covenants, 5 Jun 1700; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 2, no 11; GB/418/Main/2/3/10; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment for 2000 years to attend the inheritance of Edward Bent's estate in Kersal, 3 Jun 1700; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 2, no 12; GB/418/Main/2/3/11; Chetham's Library
    - Counterpart lease from Edward Bent to Nathan Arderne of land in Kersal, 6 Jun 1700; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 2, no 13; GB/418/Main/2/3/12; Chetham's Library
    - Memorandum concerning money lent to Edward Bent, [?1695]; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 2, no 14; GB/418/Main/2/3/13; Chetham's Library
    - List of payments paid to Edward Bent by Samuel Chetham, Jun 1709; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 2, no 15; GB/418/Main/2/3/14; Chetham's Library
    - Marriage settlement between George Chetham and Abigail Celsthorpe, 31 May 1639; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 3, no 16; GB/418/Main/2/3/15; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Kersal for £900, 7 Apr 1647; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 3, no 17; GB/418/Main/2/3/16; Chetham's Library
      From William Ravald (b 1607) to John Bent of Altrincham.
    - Lease of land in Kersal, 4 Jun 1700; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 3, no 18; GB/418/Main/2/3/17; Chetham's Library
      From Edward Bent to Samuel Chetham.
    - Conveyance of land in Kersal for £500, 5 Jun 1700; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 3, no 19; GB/418/Main/2/3/18; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment of premises in Kersal for residue of 2000 years, 20 Apr 1648; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 3, no 20; GB/418/Main/2/3/19; Chetham's Library
      From John Bent to Samuel Birch and others.
    - Return in fee of land in Kersal and assignment of this land for residue of period of 2000 years, 4 Feb 1646; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 3, no 21; GB/418/Main/2/3/20; Chetham's Library
      From George Chetham of Crumpsall to John Bent of Altrincham.
    - Receipt from George [?Dombell], rent collector, for rent paid by Robert Ravald to Lenton Priory for land in Kersal, c 1540; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 4, no 22; GB/418/Main/2/3/21; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Kersal, 10 Sep 1548; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 4, no 23; GB/418/Main/2/3/22; Chetham's Library
      From Ralph Kenyon to Richard Siddall and James Chetham.
    - Appointment of Alexander Rigby to manage estates of William Ravald (1541-1587) during his minority, 23 Nov 1560; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 4, no 24; GB/418/Main/2/3/23; Chetham's Library
    - Writ of seisin allowing William Ravald (1541-1587) to take possession of the estate of his father, William Ravald (d 1560), 26 Jun 1563; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 4, no 25; GB/418/Main/2/3/24; Chetham's Library
    - Writ of seisin allowing Robert Ravald (b 1563) to take possession of the estate of his father, Robert Ravald (d 1578), 2 Jul 1584; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 4, no 26; GB/418/Main/2/3/25; Chetham's Library
      Broken Great Seal of Elizabeth I attached.
    - Writ of seisin allowing William Ravald (1579-1623) to take possession of the estate of his father, William Ravald (1541-1587)., 5 Feb 1608; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 4, no 27; GB/418/Main/2/3/26; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Kersal, 20 Feb 1628; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 4, no 28; GB/418/Main/2/3/27; Chetham's Library
      From James Chetham to Humphrey Chetham
    - Deed of covenant to suffer Common Recovery of land in Manchester and Kersal, 13 Jul 1635; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 4, no 29; GB/418/Main/2/3/28; Chetham's Library
      From James Chetham and John Dawson against William Ravald (b 1607).
    - Common Recovery at Lancaster Sessions involving James Chetham, John Dawson, Thomas Turner and land of William Ravald, 3 Aug 1635; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 4, no 30; GB/418/Main/2/3/29; Chetham's Library
    - Deed concerning land in Kersal, 6 Aug 1641; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 4, no 31; GB/418/Main/2/3/30; Chetham's Library
      Between William Ravald (b 1607) and George Chetham.
    - Deed concerning land in Kersal occupied by William Ravald (b 1607), 4 Aug 1641; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 4, no 32; GB/418/Main/2/3/31; Chetham's Library
      Between Humphrey Chetham of Turton and George Chetham of Crumpsall
    - Petition to the House of Commons concerning sale of Crown land in Kersal, [?1654]; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 4, no 33; GB/418/Main/2/3/32; Chetham's Library
      Contains many useful historical and topographical details.
    - Four schedules of deeds relating to Kersal, 16th-19th century; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 4, no 33*; GB/418/Main/2/3/33; Chetham's Library
    - Transcript of a fine between Christopher Draper and Baldwin Willoughby concerning land in Kersal, 1544; GB/418/E.7.11, folder I(ii), no 4; GB/418/Main/2/3/34; Chetham's Library
    - Bond in £40 to perform covenants in a deed, 18 Jun 1538; GB/418/E.7.11, folder I(ii), no 5; GB/418/Main/2/3/35; Chetham's Library
      From William Langley of Agecroft and Geoffrey Shakerley of Shakerley to John Wood.
    - Agreement between John Wood and William Langley concerning lease of Kersall Cell for 20 years, 18 Jun 1538; GB/418/E.7.11, folder I(ii), no 6; GB/418/Main/2/3/36; Chetham's Library
    - Transcript of a fine at Lancaster Assizes between William Bryan and Baldwin Willoughby concerning land in Kersal, 1549; GB/418/E.7.11, folder I(ii), no 7; GB/418/Main/2/3/37; Chetham's Library
    - Livery of seisin allowing James Chetham, son of Henry Chetham to inherit lands in Kersal, Manchester and Ashton, 13 Feb 1573; GB/418/E.7.11, folder I(ii), no 8; GB/418/Main/2/3/38; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from Joseph Lightbowne to George Chetham, 2 Sep 1639; GB/418/E.7.11, folder I(ii), no 9; GB/418/Main/2/3/39; Chetham's Library
    - Demise of land in Kersal, 13 Aug 1639; GB/418/E.7.11, folder I(ii), no 10; GB/418/Main/2/3/40; Chetham's Library
      From James Chetham of Crumpsall to Ellen Burges of Middlewich.
    - Agreement between owners of Kersal Manor to maintain footpaths in Kersal, 19 May 1704; GB/418/E.7.11, folder I(ii), no 14; GB/418/Main/2/3/41; Chetham's Library
      Also early 17th century schedule of deeds relating to Kersal.
    - Petition from George Kenyon concerning land in Kersal, 13 Sep 1653; GB/418/E.7.11, folder I(ii), no 15; GB/418/Main/2/3/42; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Manchester, Crumpsall and Kersal, 7 Jan 1661/2; GB/418/E.8.4 bdl 19, no 24 & 25; GB/418/Main/2/3/43; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From George Chetham of Turton to James and Elizabeth Livesey of Great Budworth.
      No. 25 endorsed Declaration of trusts of a sum of £340 payable to Mrs Eliz[abeth] Livesay under the deed within mentioned.
    - Conveyance of all lands and tenements [?in Kersal], 13 Jan 1661/2; GB/418/E.8.4 bdl 19, no 26; GB/418/Main/2/3/44; Chetham's Library
      From James and Elizabeth Livesey to George Chetham
    - Conveyance of land in Manchester, Crumpsall and Kersal, 5 May 1671; GB/418/E.8.4 bdl 19, no 27; GB/418/Main/2/3/45; Chetham's Library
      From James Chetham to James Chetham and George Travers
    - Family settlement by William Lever of Kersal of his lands in Kersal, Chetham and Manchester, 16 Jul 1645; GB/418/E.8.12A no 1; GB/418/Main/2/3/46; Chetham's Library
  - Miscellaneous documents, including documents relating to Broughton Manor, Moston, Kersal and Crumpsall, 1575-1715; GB/418/E.7.10 & E.7.11; GB/418/Main/2/4; 22 files; Chetham's Library
    - Release of Broughton Manor, 9 Apr 1575; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 34; GB/418/Main/2/4/1; Chetham's Library
      From W Kirkby and R Redmayne to Henry, Earl of Derby.
    - Fine: George Chetham v Ferdinando Stanly and Ursula his wife, 16 Mar 1638; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 35; GB/418/Main/2/4/2; Chetham's Library
    - Fine: W Gelthorpe v G Chetham and E Chetham, Manchester, Kersal and Crumpsall, 29 Aug 1663; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 36; GB/418/Main/2/4/3; Chetham's Library
    - Fine: G Chetham v Ferdinando Stanley and Ursula (re Broughton Manor), 29 Aug 1667; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 37; GB/418/Main/2/4/4; Chetham's Library
    - Recovery: R Penington et al v J Chetham, 29 Aug 1667; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 38; GB/418/Main/2/4/5; Chetham's Library
    - Recovery: J Shelmerdine et al v R Whalley, Salford, 21 Mar 1688; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 39; GB/418/Main/2/4/6; Chetham's Library
    - Commission for taking the answer of James Chetham to bill of complaint of Ferdinando Stanley, 8 Nov 1685; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 40; GB/418/Main/2/4/7; Chetham's Library
    - Award ratified by order of court: A Drinkwater and others v J Buxton, 28 Jan 1694; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 41; GB/418/Main/2/4/8; Chetham's Library
    - Deed and counterpart concerning Moston and Broughton, 26 Mar 1698; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 42; GB/418/Main/2/4/9; Chetham's Library
      George Chetham v James Bury, his wife and son.
    - Recovery of land in Broughton, 22 Mar 1705; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 43; GB/418/Main/2/4/10; Chetham's Library
      John Clough v George Chetham.
    - Fine: Roger Sedgwick and others v Jonathon Stockton and Mary his wife. Manchester, 23 Mar 1711; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 44; GB/418/Main/2/4/11; Chetham's Library
      (Deed and counterpart)
    - Fine: W Latus and others v Jonathon Stockton and Mary his wife (Manchester), 28 Mar 1713; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 45; GB/418/Main/2/4/12; Chetham's Library
    - Fine: R Jackson and others v Edward Wood and Mary his wife (Manchester), 18 Mar 1714; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 46; GB/418/Main/2/4/13; Chetham's Library
    - Fine: Samuel Clowes and William Davenport v Jonathon Stockton and Mary his wife (Manchester), 18 Mar 1714; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 47; GB/418/Main/2/4/14; Chetham's Library
    - Fine concerning land in Withington, Blakely and Manchester, 25 Mar 1715; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 48; GB/418/Main/2/4/15; Chetham's Library
      Robert Oliver and others v Edmund Fletcher and Margaret his wife, Jonathon Stockton and Mary his wife.
    - Recovery [of land in Salford], 2 Sep 1718; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 49; GB/418/Main/2/4/16; Chetham's Library
      John Widdows v Hugh Parr
    - Fine [concerning land in Worsley and Salford], 14 Aug 1727; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 50; GB/418/Main/2/4/17; Chetham's Library
      John Walker v Hugh Parr
    - Indictment of Samuel Clowes jun and Thomas Hadfield re constableship of Manchester, 5 Sep 1728; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 51; GB/418/Main/2/4/18; Chetham's Library
    - Fine [concerning land in Salford], 5 Sep 1739; GB/418/E.7.10, folder 5, no 52; GB/418/Main/2/4/19; Chetham's Library
      James Chetham v John Thorpe and others.
    - Covenant to levy a fine of premises in Manchester, 20 Sep 1609; GB/418/E.7.11, folder I(i), no 1; GB/418/Main/2/4/20; Chetham's Library
      From Lawrence Langley and George Proudlove to William Holte and William Langley.
    - Lease for possession of land in Barnaston, co Derbys, 20 Apr 1672; GB/418/E.7.11, folder I(i), no 2; GB/418/Main/2/4/21; Chetham's Library
      From Samuel Sleigh of Etwall, kt, and James Chetham of Turton to Samuel Sleigh jun, Edwad Sleigh of Gray's Inn and James Chetham
    - Lease for a year of land in Barnaston, 24 Apr 1672; GB/418/E.7.11, folder I(i), no 3; GB/418/Main/2/4/22; Chetham's Library
      From Samuel Sleigh and James Chetham to Samuel Sleigh, Edward Sleigh and James Chetham.
  - Documents relating to the estate of the Ravald Family of Kersal, 1677-1757; GB/418/E.8.13; GB/418/Main/2/5; 25 files; Chetham's Library
    This property originally belonged to Kersal Cell and was acquired by Robert Ravald of Kersal in 1548.
    - Indentures of lease and release tripartite concerning Robert Ravald's estate in Kersal, 20 & 23 Aug 1677; GB/418/Main/2/5/1; Chetham's Library
      Between (1)Robert Ravald the elder of Kersal (b 1610), Robert Ravald the younger of Kersal (1643-1725), (2) Thomas Staynerod of Manchester, Gervase Staynerod of Manchester, (3) John Dauntesey of Edgecroft, James Chetham of Chetham.
      2 deeds pinned together
    - Grant of messuages, tenements, closes, lands etc in Kersal, 24 Jan 1709; GB/418/E.8.13 no 3a & 3b; GB/418/Main/2/5/2; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      Robert Ravald of Kersal (1643-1725), Oswald Mosley of Ancoats, Nathan Ardern of Reddish, John Hall of Droylsden.
    - Bargain and sale of messuages, tenement, closes etc in Kersal, 23 Jan 1709; GB/418/E.8.13 no 3c; GB/418/Main/2/5/3; Chetham's Library
      Robert Ravald of Kersal (1643-1725), Oswald Mosley and Nathan Ardern.
    - Court copy of will of Robert Ravald (1643-1725), 18 May 1723; GB/418/Main/2/5/4; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment and counterpart of land in Kersal and Broughton, 10 May 1710; GB/418/E.8.13 no 5; GB/418/Main/2/5/5; Chetham's Library
      From Robert Ravald (1643-1725) to Oswald Ravald (d 1722)
    - Court copy of will of Oswald Ravald (d 1722), 2 Oct 1721; GB/418/E.8.13 no 6; GB/418/Main/2/5/6; Chetham's Library
    - Bargain and sale of messuages and tenements and parcels of land in Kersal, 21 Mar 1739; GB/418/E.8.13 no 7; GB/418/Main/2/5/7; Chetham's Library
      Between Oswald Ravald of Worsley (1718-1771) and Peter Heywood of Manchester
    - Recovery of Kersal lands at Lancaster by Oswald Ravald (1718-1771), 22 Mar 1739; GB/418/E.8.13 no 8; GB/418/Main/2/5/8; Chetham's Library
    - Pleas at the Lancaster assizes concerning lands in Kersal, 24 Mar 1739; GB/418/E.8.13 no 9; GB/418/Main/2/5/9; Chetham's Library
      George Ridings, James Hall against Peter Heywood and Oswald Ravald (1718-1771)
    - Receipt from John Gatley and Mary Ravald of share of £200 from Oswald Ravald, 26 Apr 1740; GB/418/E.8.13 no 10; GB/418/Main/2/5/10; Chetham's Library
    - Receipt from Hannah Ravald of her share of £200 from Oswald Ravald, 18 Nov 1740; GB/418/E.8.13 no 11; GB/418/Main/2/5/11; Chetham's Library
    - Bargain and sale of messuages, tenements, tenements, closes, lands etc in Kersal, 25 Apr 1740; GB/418/E.8.13 no 12; GB/418/Main/2/5/12; Chetham's Library
      From Oswald Ravald to James Walker of Manchester
    - Release of lands etc in Kersal, 26 Apr 1740; GB/418/E.8.13 no 13; GB/418/Main/2/5/13; Chetham's Library
      From Oswald Ravald to James Walker
    - Grant, bargain and sale of messuages, closes, lands etc in Kersal, 26 Mar 1754; GB/418/E.8.13 no 14; GB/418/Main/2/5/14; Chetham's Library
      From Oswald Ravald to James Hall
    - Assignment of a term of 500 years affecting premises in Kersal, 28 Aug 1754; GB/418/E.8.13 no 15; GB/418/Main/2/5/15; Chetham's Library
      From James Hall to James Hilton
    - Writ of common recovery, 29 Aug 1754; GB/418/E.8.13 no 16; GB/418/Main/2/5/16; Chetham's Library
    - Bargain and sale to Edward Chetham of messuage and tenement in Kersal, 9 Sep 1756; GB/418/E.8.13 no 17; GB/418/Main/2/5/17; Chetham's Library
      John Walker, James Hall, James Massey, John Gatley and Thomas Gardner, Oswald Ravald and John Ravald, and Edward Chetham of Castleton
    - Unidentified document, 10 Sep 1756; GB/418/E.8.13 no 18; GB/418/Main/2/5/18; Chetham's Library
      John Walker, George Lloyd, Thomas Clowes / James Hall / James Massey, John Gatley, Thomas Gardner, Oswald Ravald / John Ravald / Edward Chetham
    - Mary Birch: Release of £200 in Robert Ravald's will, 1 Oct 1756; GB/418/E.8.13 no 19; GB/418/Main/2/5/19; Chetham's Library
    - Release of lands in Kersal, 21 Mar 1757; GB/418/E.8.13 no 20; GB/418/Main/2/5/20; Chetham's Library
      From John Morris, John Gatley to Edward Chetham
    - John Morris: Acquittal of right to Ravald estate, 14 Aug 1756; GB/418/E.8.13 no 21; GB/418/Main/2/5/21; Chetham's Library
    - Agreement concerning land in Kersal, 14 Feb 1755; GB/418/E.8.13 no 22; GB/418/Main/2/5/22; Chetham's Library
      Between Oswald Ravald of Little Hulton (1718-1771) and Edward Chetham of Castleton
    - Recovery at Lancaster, 11 Sep 1756; GB/418/E.8.13 no 23; GB/418/Main/2/5/23; Chetham's Library
      Concerning Oswald and John Ravald
    - Case upon Oswald Ravald's settlement of the Kersal estate, 23 Oct 1740; GB/418/E.8.13 no 24; GB/418/Main/2/5/24; Chetham's Library
    - Abstract of Oswald Ravald's title to Kersal estate, [1754-1757]; GB/418/E.8.13 no 25; GB/418/Main/2/5/25; Chetham's Library
      With small bundle of letters concerning Kersal estate.
  - Documents relating to Pendleton and Ordsall, 1639-1746; GB/418/E.7.11, folder II, no; GB/418/Main/2/6; 11 files; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Pendleton, 12 Feb 1685; GB/418/E.7.11, folder II, no 16; GB/418/Main/2/6/1; Chetham's Library
      From James Chetham to Nathan Leech and John Waite
    - Lease for 6 months and conveyance of land in Pendleton, 11 Feb 1685; GB/418/E.7.11, fdr II, 17 & 22; GB/418/Main/2/6/2; 2 items; Chetham's Library
    - Release of land in Pendleton, 12 Feb 1685; GB/418/E.7.11, folder II, no 18; GB/418/Main/2/6/3; Chetham's Library
      From James Chetham to John Waite
    - Conveyance of land in Pendleton and Ordsall, 11 Mar 1639; GB/418/E.7.11, folder II, no 19; GB/418/Main/2/6/4; Chetham's Library
      From Alexander Radcliffe of Ordsall to Humphrey Chetham
    - Conveyance of land in Pendleton and Ordsall, 20 Aug 1656; GB/418/E.7.11, folder II, no 20; GB/418/Main/2/6/5; Chetham's Library
      From John Radclythe of Ordsall to Edward Chetham of Chetham.
    - Bill concerning work involved with Chetham's purchase of Dr Chaddock's lands in Salford, 17 Apr 1746; GB/418/E.7.11, folder II, no 21; GB/418/Main/2/6/6; Chetham's Library
      From Christopher Byron to James Chetham
    - Lease for 6 months of land in Pendleton, Pendlebury and Salford, 11 Feb 1685; GB/418/E.7.11, folder II, no 23; GB/418/Main/2/6/7; Chetham's Library
    - Release of land in Pendleton, Pendlebury, Ordsall, Salford and Manchester, 12 Feb 1685; GB/418/E.7.11, folder II, no 24; GB/418/Main/2/6/8; Chetham's Library
      From Henry Chetham to John Waite and Nathan Leech.
    - Deed of exchange concerning land in Ordsall, Pendleton and Pendlebury, 18 Sep 1665; GB/418/E.7.11, folder II, no 25; GB/418/Main/2/6/9; Chetham's Library
      Between John Birch of Whitborne, Herefordshire and Edward Chetham of Chetham.
    - Final concord concerning lands in Ordsall, Pendleton and Pendlebury, 3 Apr 1658; GB/418/E.7.11, folder II, no 26; GB/418/Main/2/6/10; Chetham's Library
      Between Edward Chetham and John Radcliffe.
    - Grant of lands in Manchester and Eccles, 21 May 1654; GB/418/E.7.11, folder II, no 27; GB/418/Main/2/6/11; Chetham's Library
      From Sir Alexander Radcliffe, Humphrey Booth and Lawrence Bradshawe to Humphrey Chetham.
  - Documents concerning James Chetham of Chetham and James Chetham of Smedley, 1603-1737; GB/418/E.7.11 & E.7.12; GB/418/Main/2/7; 10 files; Chetham's Library
    - Marriage settlement of James Chetham, 1607; GB/418/E.7.11, folder III, no 28; GB/418/Main/2/7/1; Chetham's Library
    - Marriage settlement of James Chetham of Smedley, 25 Apr 1672; GB/418/E.7.11, fldr III, no 29 & 30; GB/418/Main/2/7/2; 2 items; Chetham's Library
    - Detached seal from livery of seisin granted to James Chetham, 1603; GB/418/E.7.11, folder III, no 31; GB/418/Main/2/7/3; Chetham's Library
    - Lease and release of land in Salford, 4 & 5 May 1684; GB/418/E.7.12, folder II, no 22; GB/418/Main/2/7/4; Chetham's Library
      From Mary Byron of Salford, James Chetham of Chetham et al to William Bury of Salford
    - Will of William Berry of Salford, 5 Jun 1709; GB/418/E.7.12, folder II, no 23; GB/418/Main/2/7/5; Chetham's Library
    - Lease and release of land in Salford, 9 & 10 Dec 1731; GB/418/E.7.12, folder II, no 24; GB/418/Main/2/7/6; Chetham's Library
      From Richard Bury of Salford, the elder to Richard Bury of Salford the younger
    - Conveyance of land in Oldfield, 15 Mar 1737; GB/418/E.7.12, folder II, no 25; GB/418/Main/2/7/7; Chetham's Library
      From Richard and Elizabeth Bury of Salford to James Chetham of Smedley
    - Bond in £390 from Richard Bury of Salford to James Chetham of Smedley, 15 Mar 1737; GB/418/E.7.12, folder II, no 26; GB/418/Main/2/7/8; Chetham's Library
    - Article of agreement between Richard Bury of Salford and James Chetham of Smedley concerning land in Oldfield Lane, Salford, 1 Jan 1737; GB/418/E.7.12, folder II, no 27; GB/418/Main/2/7/9; Chetham's Library
    - Schedule of deeds, 17th-18th century; GB/418/E.7.12, folder II, no 28; GB/418/Main/2/7/10; Chetham's Library
    - Receipts for items supplied for the funeral of James Chetham of Smedley on 5 Feb 1752, 11 Feb-20 Feb 1752; GB/418/E.8.10 no 30 (a-o); GB/418/Main/2/7/11; 15 items; Chetham's Library
      - Funeral receipt for materials to be used in mourning at the funeral of James Chetham on 5 Feb 1752, supplied by Edward Byrom, 20 Feb 1752; GB/418/E.8.10 no 30 (a); GB/418/Main/2/7/11/1; Chetham's Library
      - Funeral receipt from William Blinkhorn for money received for supplying stockings for James Chetham's funeral, 11 Feb 1752; GB/418/E.8.10 no 30 (b); GB/418/Main/2/7/11/2; Chetham's Library
      - Funeral receipt from Mr Fletcher for money received for church and burial expenses at James Chetham's funeral, 11 Feb 1752; GB/418/E.8.10 no 30 (c); GB/418/Main/2/7/11/3; Chetham's Library
      - Funeral receipt from Tho[ma]s Hampton for money received for supplying a hearse and pair and a mourning coach and six for James Chetham's funeral, 12 Feb 1752; GB/418/E.8.10 no 30 (d); GB/418/Main/2/7/11/4; Chetham's Library
      - Funeral receipt from Edward Jackson to Mrs Ann Chetham for money received for supplying oak coffin for funeral of James Chetham, 12 Feb 1752; GB/418/E.8.10 no 30 (e); GB/418/Main/2/7/11/5; Chetham's Library
      - Funeral receipt from John Rostom for money received for supplying food and drink for James Chetham's funeral, 13 Feb 1752; GB/418/E.8.10 no 30 (f); GB/418/Main/2/7/11/6; Chetham's Library